Get ready to get naughty!
The Smurfs 2 is a fantasy, family, comedy film directed by Raja Gosnell.
The evil wizard Gargamel creates a couple of mischievous Smurf-like creatures called the
Naughties that he hopes will let him harness the all-powerful, magical Smurf-essence.
But when he discovers that only a real Smurf can give him what he wants, and only a secret spell that Smurfette knows can turn the Naughties into real
Smurfs, Gargamel kidnaps Smurfette and brings her to Paris, where he has been winning the adoration of millions as the world¹s greatest sorcerer.
It's up to Papa, Clumsy, Grouchy, and Vanity to return to our world, reunite with
their human friends Patrick and Grace Winslow, and rescue her!
Will Smurfette, who has always felt different from the other Smurfs, find a new connection with the
Naughties Vexy and Hackus or will the Smurfs convince her that their love for her is True Blue?
Smurfette (voice), played by Katy Perry.
Gargamel, played by Hank Azaria.
Patrick Winslow, played by Neil Patrick Harris.
Grace Winslow, played by Jayma Mays.
Victor Doyle, played by Brendan Gleeson.
Blue Winslow, played by Jacob Tremblay.
Smurfs is a 2025 American live-action animated musical fantasy comedy film based on
The Smurfs comic book series created by the Belgian comics artist Peyo.
A reboot of The Smurfs film series, the film was directed
by Chris Miller and written by Pam Brady.
It stars Rihanna, who also produces the film, as the voice of Smurfette, alongside an ensemble cast including James Corden, Nick Offerman, JP Karliak, Daniel Levy, Amy
Sedaris, Natasha Lyonne, Sandra Oh, Jimmy Kimmel, Octavia Spencer, Nick Kroll, Hannah Waddingham, Alex Winter, Maya Erskine, Kurt Russell, and John Goodman.
In February 2022, it was reported that Lafig S.A.
and IMPS, now known as Peyo Company, the owners of the Smurfs brand, had agreed to a partnership with Paramount
Animation to produce multiple animated Smurfs films, with the first project being a musical.
Brady was attached to write the screenplay, with
production set to begin later that year.
By June 2022, Miller had been hired to direct the film, and by April 2023, Rihanna had joined the
film as a voice actor and producer, along with writing and recording original songs.
Animation services were provided by Cinesite.
Smurfs premiered in Brussels on June 28, 2025, and was released by
Paramount Pictures in the United States on July 18.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics and, despite grossing over $124.1 million worldwide,
was ultimately considered to be a box-office disappointment and lost $80 million for Paramount.
The film explores themes of magic, based on comic,
aftercreditsstinger, duringcreditsstinger, live action and animation.
The tone is lighthearted.